hello this is Frankie Freitas and we're
here at the center for holographic arts
in Long Island City
better known as queens and I'm speaking
with Shu minlin how are you hi good hi
everybody how are you okay
um you've been involved with holography
for how long uh has been about 10 years
10 years now and what do you work in as
most of the work that you do in
reflection holography or white light
transmission holography I do most of uh
reflection hologram but I kind of
working on more in much larger scale by
having a hologram into the installation
so for example one of my work I install
the hologram on the floor and the floor
take about 1 000 square feet space and
the uh the entire holographic
installation is that size um that will
be about like uh for that piece that
particular one I have a one about 100
Holograms mixers of tiles so people the
audience can be walk on the the tiles
and also
look at a hologram now is this an
exhibit that moves from place to place
part of your work or is this an exhibit
that's in a building that's there
permanently uh this piece has been
traveled to many different countries and
currently are shown in Finland
and most of time was in the museum space
and kind of keep traveling now yeah
what's your background is your
background more as an artist or in
science and technology uh Fine Arts my
background Fine Arts what Drew you to
holography were you involved with
another medium first and uh sort of like
changed over to holography or with
holography your first love well
um yeah before that is I kind of you
know play with all different medium like
a painting or a sculpture those things
um but it's kind of I always feel like a
two-dimensional painting there are too
flat 2D and the sculpture to me is also
kind of little too real so until about
10 years to go when I first time I saw
hologram I finally found these two
elements these two quality can be
combining together you
do you have your own laboratory yes I do
um I have my studio in Manhattan okay
yeah and what do you have inside what
type of laser systems are you working
with right now I have a uh neon laser
and also um a big table for that the
table weighs 2 000 pounds yeah
um so and also some other side
facilities do you know what the power of
a laser is is a 50 meter one
125 Spectra yeah you know pretty well
um
looking in holography do you find some
sometimes you become frustrated because
there's only so much you can do with the
technology
um
I have to say as a holographer you
always have to you know there are so
many things unknown and happen during
the the working you know procedure but
but frustration never really coming from
the limitation because I do feel maybe
different Auto holographic I do feel
there are still so many things you can
do for this medium and um you know apply
to different ideas there's so many odd
you know things I haven't done yet
um and you know if sometimes you get
frustrated maybe because like uh you
know every good work requires so many
um you know requirements like a
stability or temperature whatever so
many things sometimes you don't get a
very good result and you have to
researching to see what happened and
that can sometimes you have no way
to find out because there are not many
people involved in this field and the
support may be not enough but other than
that I'm pretty happy what's what's your
process of coming up with a holographic
work uh do you sit down and think of a
concept and perhaps maybe draw it out on
paper first or is there a process that
you find yourself going into from start
to finish with a with a piece
um amounts of pieces they'll be coming
from all different directions but yeah I
do have to you know make a whole
proposal together since I might type
hologram it requires like a like a lot
of multi-exposures so sometimes I feel
it's kind of like even like a Film
Production I have to have a you know
after concept and after the idea
starting to develop I maybe even do a
storyboard or I even having a people
actual people who are finally I'm I'm
going to be in my hologram I will took
the photo first as my sketch
there's so many Holograms out there
where it's just the Hologram and like
you had mentioned earlier you work with
installations and there are other
elements that are involved with your
holographic work as well what are some
of the things that you've combined with
holography in your projects
um so far the things I'm combining is
all the different material objects like
some like a for example I love the piece
like glass vase or the other the other
piece I'm mounting the hologram on the
fish tank
and uh and then you know I'm also will
be working on more and more combining
with some other materials
or some other art form together
I've I've been involved with holography
for many years as well and I know that
there's been comments out there saying
that
you know some people feel holography is
a legitimate art form other people do
not and I would think that after all
these years that that argument would
have gone away but it still seems to be
fairly prevalent out there
how do you feel that this medium of
holography could be looked upon as a
legitimate art form a lot of times when
you go out to see a hologram you'll see
a hologram of something of an object and
for most people you know why not just
sit the object there instead of making a
hologram of it what's different about
the type of work that you do that gets
away from that thing of just reproducing
something that already exists well to
look at that perspective like even
painting Iris kind of reproduce them oh
that's true yes even the photography
there will produce something so I think
the value is not how exactly these
things reproduce the real object it's
how and it's all according to how what
kind of meaning the art is put into that
work
otherwise I guess AVR world will produce
something else
so
um I don't know why I guess the Hologram
is a limitation is not a lot of people
really know and also not a lot of people
able to get into this medium so this
medium always kind of has been you know
you know so far not that popular so you
know people kind of looking at that in a
very interesting way because people keep
thinking about the technical side rather
than what the actual content those
artists put into there because what
grabbing you first is always wow that's
so amazing why why are you doing this
how this happening so I guess that was
something you know how people feel that
but I guess if anyone who are seriously
um or some are critique for all like any
any audience or any
um you know that you could get really
more serious about work then they will
get in there and then see what's a real
expression the artists try to put in
there it's like every the other medium
like even I guess even oil painting in
one time was a new medium too and high
tech at one time yeah so a pencil was
high-tech at one time yeah so this is
just like we are kind of maybe in the
time frame we are a little earlier so we
have to be able to answer most of those
questions about technical side
what are the biggest barriers to having
people get involved with holography what
could we change about holography that
would allow more people the opportunity
to get involved with it do you feel well
first of all it's about this
um it requires so many agreements
this they make a very different than
other uh our medium and those agreements
you know is making like a normal like
our student they couldn't really reach
and touch or to get in there and then to
spend enough time it's like also like an
even computer at the beginning you know
you see like all the students squeeze
into one room and they all started from
one big screen and now everyone got one
in school and one at home so it's about
like I guess I guess you have to make
the equipment more
um available for people and then that
really depends on what you know if
there's any like a your company they
will be willing to putting more effort
into this to make this more popular do
you think some of the companies that are
dealing with these Technologies such as
the laser manufacturers your Optical
manufacturers and the people who
manufacture the mounts do you think that
they should be putting more money back
into the field to help people get
involved with it it doesn't seem as if
these companies contribute anything back
into the field
yeah it doesn't seem they're doing that
but I would like to see that because
like you know if one day these things
become more available for people then
um back to just now we're talking about
people keep thinking about this
technology things it's like nobody will
asking anyone how the photo developed
even nobody knows
and how the city like a Music City
contact disk how that works and nobody
knows but because it's so popular so
nobody asks
yeah where do you see holography going
in the future as far as maybe 10 or 20
years down the road
um
first I'd like to find out what some of
your Visions are on that and then I'll
get back to you maybe asking you what do
you think needs to take place in order
for us to get there but but where would
you like to see holography in 10 years
what do you think we're going to be
seeing with it
you know since this medium is so
attractive you know by how many times
when I had a show and how you think how
people the audience responds to the
world you know you know people like this
and um
so it's like a feel like a very you know
interesting like it doesn't really go
that far so far but but if the things
are very attractive to people and you
know I there's no reason it doesn't get
big
so I will see like it's supposed to be
in the future
um maybe those things can instead of
I mean the closest one will be
photography
um the photo ID whatever
um
I think the ID will be the the most
closest one like uh that can be
releasing three-dimensional you know
people on the photo or ID yeah
and in order to get there what do you
think we need to overcome what are some
of the barriers that you see to getting
there
again still back to the equipment's not
that available and um and you need to
have a kind of more and I guess
individually the those holographer if
they don't have enough funding then you
cannot really push that far so again
they still have you know we have to see
if there's any bigger manufacturing
company they related to this and they'll
be willing to put more energy on this
side that's that's an issue that I hear
a lot about as far as an artist will say
that they don't have any funding so that
they can't do any work
I I try to you know I still try to you
know using hologram to make a bigger
hologram so somehow you know you know if
someone purchased a hologram and put
that money back to produce the bigger
work and sometimes I have some
commission work and I use that part of
money to do you know to kind of going
back to for the next project
yeah and yeah that's the way it kind of
self-sufficient in that way how can
someone find out more about your work
okay
um I have a website no I'm going to have
but now
um and the I I because I I kind of show
very frequently
um I almost have about usually about 10
exhibitions in one year and uh yeah I
should have my website that's it yeah
okay and we will include information
I see you have your card here so would
it be all right for us to put your
telephone number in case and your email
address as well of course yeah and if
anyone
um you know heard this from the from the
news any of you have any question please
welcome to call me or you can email to
me should I just my yeah my phone number
same as my fax number is area code 212.
662-5966 and my email address is uh L I
N Lim l-i-n at sprintmail.com
l-i-n at s p r i n t n a i l.com and my
name is
spelled s-h-u
iPhone m i n shumin Lin Lin I want to
thank you very much for being on the
show it was very nice meeting you yeah
me too thank you we'll see you next week
everyone take care